Jakub Pietraszek

EXPERIENCE

National Information Processing Institute

JULY 2022 - PRESENT

Junior Data Scientist

- Created NLP model for specifying specialization of polish researchers based on papers topic.
- Currently involved in development and maintenance Hadoop cluster with Spark and several other services.

McKinsey - XAI Stories 3

MARCH 2022 - JUNE 2022

- eXplainable Artificial Intelligence project under McKinsey leadership, based on mBank data and with MIMUW theoretical background.
- The main aim was to make an understandable and explainable black-box model for the banking sector.

ULTRAdventure

DECEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2022

Data Analyst and IT admin

- Created and maintained online store.
- Created reports based on data from social media and Google Analytics/Search Console.

SKILLS

- Python: Numpy, Pandas, Sklearn, Pyspark, Tensorflow, Pytorch, BERTopic, top2vec, Plotly, Seaborn, Pyplot
- SQL: Oracle, Spark, DeltaLake
- R
- Linux: Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS7, RHEL9
- · VScode, Jupyter
- conda environments, docker
- Git
- Jira, Confluence

COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

- Google Data AnalyticsProfessional Certificate 2022
- DATACAMP
 Data Scientist and Data Engineer Career Paths
 2022
- Udemy Data Engineering 2022

yaaqbp@gmail.com

github.com/yaaqbp

+48 884 165 969

in linkedin.com/in/jakub-pietraszek

ABOUT ME

I am a detail-oriented person with analytical skills focused on problem solving. I have experience in data science and machine learning, currentlyI also have a strong desire to develop in data engineering and bigdata development. I want to make not only Jupyter-based theoretical models but rather real-world applications.

INTERESTS

Outside of work, I really like cycling. For several years I had a strong passion for ultra-racing, now I prefer it to be a moment of break and time to look for inspiration.

LANGUAGES

Polish - native English - B2

EDUCATION

University of Lodz Data Analysis

2020 - PRESENT

BSc in the Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science.

Wroclaw University of Science and Technology Quantum Engineering / Theoretical Physics 2019 - 2020

Member of Nabla and Quantum Computing student bodies.

I agree to the processing of personal data provided in this document for realising the recruitment process pursuant to the Personal Data Protection Act of 10 May 2018 (Journal of Laws 2018, item 1000) and in agreement with Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation).